<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Jeffrey A. Walker</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Jeffrey A. Walker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography I am a Professor of Biological Sciences at the University of Southern Maine. My research background is in evolutionary and ecological morphology, whole-animal performance, and biomechanics of swimming and flying. Most of my current research is in statistical best practices applied to problems in ecology and physiology /cell biology. These research problems are largely motivated by the classes that I teach, which include the Ecology/Evolution/Diversity semester of our Introductory Biology sequence, Human Physiology (a year-long sequence for Biology majors), and Applied Biostatistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Apps</title>
      <link>/home/shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/shiny/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R doodles</title>
      <link>/home/rdoodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/rdoodles/</guid>
      <description>What is an R doodle? An R doodle is a short script to check intuition or understanding. Almost always, this involves generating fake data.
Where can I find R doodles? Here. Some of these will be expanded into longer, interactive quasi-publications. Some of these might be fleshed out into manuscripts for archiving at PeerJ preprints or bioR$\chi$iv. Others will be expanded into Shiny apps. Some I might even submit for publication in a journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive quasi-publications</title>
      <link>/home/prepreprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/prepreprints/</guid>
      <description>Combining data, distribution summary, model effects, and uncertainty in a single plot Pre-preprint Shiny
Bias in pre-post designs &amp;ndash; An example from the Turnbaugh et al (2006) mouse fecal transplant study Pre-preprint</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications and working papers</title>
      <link>/home/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/pubs/</guid>
      <description>A full-list is found at my Google Scholar page. PDFs can be found at my Research Gate page.
Walker, J.A. (2017). On Model Averaging Partial Regression Coefficients. BioRxiv 133785. bioRxiv
Walker, J.A. (2016). Monte Carlo simulation of OLS and linear mixed model inference of phenotypic effects on gene expression. PeerJ 4, e2575. PeerJ
Walker, J.A., and Caddigan, S.P. (2015). Performance trade-offs and individual quality in decathletes. Journal of Experimental Biology 218, 3647–3657.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Materials</title>
      <link>/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Lots more to come
Physics for Introductory Biology HTML</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>