<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jeffrey A. Walker</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jeffrey A. Walker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of statistics in bench biology: Fc-dependent depletion of tumor-infiltrating regulatory T cells co-defines the efficacy of anti–CTLA-4 therapy against melanoma</title>
      <link>/post/the-role-of-statistics-in-bench-biology-fc-dependent-depletion-of-tumor-infiltrating-regulatory-t-cells-co-defines-the-efficacy-of-anti-ctla-4-therapy-against-melanoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-role-of-statistics-in-bench-biology-fc-dependent-depletion-of-tumor-infiltrating-regulatory-t-cells-co-defines-the-efficacy-of-anti-ctla-4-therapy-against-melanoma/</guid>
      <description>Experiment 1 Fig 1C. “GVAX+–CTLA-4 combination therapy protects against tumor outgrowth through a CD4+ T cell–dependent mechanism”
 2 x 2 combination of GVAX and alpha-CTLA-4 on tumor growth in C57BL/6 wild-type and I-A-/- (no CD4+ T cell compartment) mouse lines. Combination treatment (but not either in isolation) “protected against” tumor growth in wild but not -/- mice, indicating CD4+ T cell required for protection.
Treatment key: -/- control; +/- alpha-CTLA-4; -/+ GVAX; +/+ both cell key: CD4+Foxp3- Teff; CD4+Foxp3+ Treg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of statistics in Boström: &#34;A PGC1-alpha-dependent myokine that drives brown-fat-like development of white fat and thermogenesis&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/comments-on-the-role-of-statistics-in-bostr%C3%B6m-a-pgc1-alpha-dependent-myokine-that-drives-brown-fat-like-development-of-white-fat-and-thermogenesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/comments-on-the-role-of-statistics-in-bostr%C3%B6m-a-pgc1-alpha-dependent-myokine-that-drives-brown-fat-like-development-of-white-fat-and-thermogenesis/</guid>
      <description>Muscle PGC1-a transgenics (Figure 1 and S1) The transgenic mice are expressing PGC1-a in skeletal muscle. These mice seem to be overexpressing browning related proteins in white adipose tissue. The section argues that this pattern suggests muscle is secreting a myokine that signals fat.
results reported in text Fig. 1a shows the “relative mRNA” of brown-fat-selective genes between wild-type and transgenic mice in two different fat depots. The authors write: “There were no significant alterations in the expression of brown-fat-selective genes in the interscapular brown adipose tissue or in the visceral (epididymal) white adipose tissue (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I interpret the AIC?</title>
      <link>/post/how-do-i-interpret-the-aic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-do-i-interpret-the-aic/</guid>
      <description>This is an archive of an external source. The original is here
Date: xxx
Author: Chris Brown
How do I interpret the AIC?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting coefficients in GLMs</title>
      <link>/post/interpreting-coefficients-in-glms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interpreting-coefficients-in-glms/</guid>
      <description>This is an archive of an external source. The original is here
Date: November 11, 2016
Author: Gordana Popovic
In linear models, the interpretation of model parameters is linear. For example, if a you were modelling plant height against altitude and your coefficient for altitude was -0.9, then plant height will decrease by 1.09 for every increase in altitude of 1 unit.
For generalised linear models, the interpretation is not this straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Intuition Behind Hierarchical Modeling</title>
      <link>/post/some-intuition-behind-hierarchical-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/some-intuition-behind-hierarchical-modeling/</guid>
      <description>This is an archive of an external source
Date: November 13, 2017
Author: Kert Viele
Hierarchical modeling is a powerful tool for making inferences about multiple groups in clinical trials, whether these groups are multiple indications or tumor types in an oncology study, multiple sites in a device clinical trial, or any other source of patient heterogeneity.
Hierarchical models that share information across groups form a backbone of modern Bayesian thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>